

# **MUBASHIR MOHSIN**

Currently in the final semester of B.Sc. in Computer Science and Engineering

## CONTACT



Mirpur, Dhaka, Bangladesh - 1216



mubashir.mohsin.42884@gmail.com



+88 0172-6331487

### LINKS



linkedin.com/in/mubashir-mohsin



github.com/Mubashir42884

## **SKILLS**



Python



**R-Programming** 



\_





C#

## **LANGUAGES**

English  $\star \star \star \star \star$ 

Bengali ★★★★

## **HOBBIES**

- Playing and Watching Football.
- Drawing and sketching.
- Watching Movies and Series.

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

As a dedicated Computer Science graduate, with a major in Data Science, Data Mining, and Management Information Systems, complemented by Machine Learning and Computer Vision. Driven by an intense interest in cutting-edge technology, I have combined my academic path with practical research in the fields of cybersecurity, cancer healthcare, and artificial intelligence. My goal in life is to be an inspiration in the fields of data science and AI/ML in my own country Bangladesh.

#### **WORK HISTORY**

Jan 2022 -Jun 2022 Information Technology Consultant, BM Abroad Dreamers (<u>Link</u>), Dhaka, Bangladesh.

 Ensured seamless IT operations, managed information systems securely, and advised on efficient business strategies.

Mar 2023 -Present Junior Graphic Designer, Fabritex Ventures (Link), Dhaka, Bangladesh

Crafted the official logo, designed posters, images, and social-media posts, contributed to a visually compelling brand presence.

#### **EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND**

Jan 2020 Jun 2024 Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Engineering, American International University-Bangladesh (AIUB), Dhaka

- CGPA: 3.81
- Major: Information Systems

Works & Projects:

- '90MinsStat Football Statistics Web-App using R'. Supervisor: Dr. Akinul Islam Jony, Computer Science Dept. Head, AIUB. (Skills: R-Programming, Data Analysis, Dashboard Generation, Web Scrapping)
- 'Creating TDIDT Algorithm from scratch and predicting Loan approval dataset'. Supervisor: Dr. Akinul Islam Jony, Computer Science Dept. Head, AIUB. (Skills: R-Programming, Data Analysis, Data Mining and Warehousing)
- 'DeepFER: Facial Emotion Recognition model using Deep Learning'. Supervisor: Dr. Debajyoti Karmaker, Associate Professor, AIUB. (Skills: Python, TensorFlow, Keras, PyTorch, Deep Learning, Computer Vision, Research Skills)
- 'HeptoPass: Multipurpose Management System WebApp'. Supervisor: Md. Al-Amin, Lecturer, AIUB. (Skills: HTML, PHP, JavaScript, AJAX, JQuery, CSS)
- 'ENABLED: A Disability Assistance System'. Supervisor: Farzana Bente Alam, Lecturer, AIUB. (Skills: Software Development Lifecycle, Project Process Models, Software Requirement Analysis, Project Diagrams, UI/UX)
- 'EMS-Pro: An Expense Management System'. Supervisor: Victor Stany Rozario, Assistant Professor, AIUB. (Skills: C#, .NET Framework, SQL, Windows Forms, Database Management System)

Jul 2017 Jan 2019

- Higher Secondary School Certificate (HSC), Dhaka Residential Model College (DRMC), Dhaka
  - Grade: A+ (GPA 5.00)
  - Activities and societies: Science Club, Olympiad, Football, Quiz.
  - Skills: Team Leadership · Fine Art · Football · C (Programming Language) HTML Scripting · Microsoft Office · Adobe Premiere Pro & Photoshop

Jan 2015 -Mar 2017 Secondary School Certificate (SSC), Dhaka Residential Model College (DRMC), Dhaka

- Grade: A+ (GPA 5.00)
- Activities and societies: Olympiad, Football, Quiz, Art & Craft.

## **PUBLICATIONS**

[1] M. Mohsin and A. I. Jony, "A Comparative Analysis of Medical IoT Device Attacks Using Machine Learning Models", Malaysian J. Sci. Adv. Tech., vol. 4, no. 4, pp. 429-439, Sep. 2024. DOI: https://doi.org/10.56532/mjsat.v4i4.318

#### CERTIFICATIONS

- July 2020 Technical Support Fundamentals Google (Link)
- October 2022 Tableau Fundamentals DataCamp (<u>Link</u>)
- November 2022 Data Analyst Track DataCamp (<u>Link</u>)
- July 2020 Cisco IT Essentials Cisco (Netacad ID: 1005989521)